What's going on, Michael? Isaiah Smalls
from the Miami Herald. Congratulations
and welcome to South Florida.
>> Hey, Isaiah. I appreciate you.
>> So, the burning question I had on my
mind was I believe you had a scholarship
to Rice. It was, and you decided, nah,
I'm want to go walk on at Texas. Walk me
through that decision.
>> I I was a fifth gen generation Longhorn,
so all my life I wanted to go to Texas.
Um, you know, my great greatgrandfather
was there. My grandfather swam there was
an all-American swimmer. My parents went
there, older brother and older sister
were there. So, uh, we grew up watching
Texas games. And, you know, Friday we
were going to Westlake varsity games.
Saturday we're going to Texas games.
That's just what we did. And, um, you
know, the the thing at Texas was you
seeing the eyes of Texas before the game
and after. And so, you know, we were
standing from eyes to eyes is what we
like to say. And um I just know that if
you believe in yourself and you do what
what you your heart is telling you to do
and um you just keep pushing and put the
team first, anything's possible.
>> And then you know you walk on obviously
have success, make it to captain,
all-American just how does someone do
that? I feel like you talked about that
belief in yourself. just how big of a
role did that play in your journey and
what do you believe that you know
leadership component what do you you
know bringing that to Miami like what do
you think the power of that is? Yeah, I
think what you can do off the field is
is essential in in the game of football.
Um, first off, but how I did it, I I
never once told myself I was going to go
be an all-American and um, you know, all
these accolades. I just was cared about
the team. When I when I got there, I was
like, "All right, I'm going to make an
impact for the University of Texas, and
that's what I wanted to do." Um, and so
it was never really about myself. And um
you know once I got that opportunity it
was like wow look what you know putting
the University of Texas first, putting
your team first, putting your teammates
first can really get you. Um so you know
I was proud of what we were able to do
at Texas. Um but it it all started off
the field with um the ability to be a
leader in there and what culture we
brought and um you know our freshman
year we were five and seven and with the
help of my coaches and my teammates we
brought a team to two semi-finals a
conference championship um three back to
backto-back 10 win plus seasons. So um
you know it started what nobody could
could see um on the field. started
inside those four walls in the locker
room and uh the brotherhood that we
made. So, um [clears throat] you know,
it's definitely a way different way to
lead going in the NFL and being a
rookie, but you got to earn your stripes
early. Um you got to put your head down
and not say a word and be humble. And
once your time is is able to talk, then
that's when you use your voice. But, um
you know, there can be leaders from the
bottom to the top. It's not always the
raw guy. There's different ways of
leading. And I'm going to find out and I
can't wait to learn from the leaders
above.
Cool. Appreciate you and congrats again.
>> Thank you,
>> David.
>> Hey, Michael. David Feronus of the South
Florida Sun Sentinel. Welcome to South
Florida and congrats on being drafted by
the Dolphins.
>> Hey, thank you, David. Nice to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you. Uh, so I understand
from your the v social media video of
your phone call with Jeff Hafley that
was unveiled on social media that you
and Quinn Eers are very good friends
from obviously time together at Texas.
Uh, what interactions have you had with
him since uh, your draft selection?
Yeah. So, I actually put my phone down
right after I got drafted and um my
agent was a little bit mad at me because
he tried to FaceTime me and um you know,
he's giving me all the intel, so I
should probably text my agent right
after I get drafted. But um you know, I
put my phone down and my buddy came up
to me. He was like, "Hey, you know, I
don't want to bother you. Keep
celebrating, but Quinn's on the line."
Uh he just facetimed me. I was like, a.
So, within two minutes of it getting
announced, uh, you know, Quinn Facetime
me and, you know, I got to talk to him
and he was just so fired up and his
girlfriend and my girlfriend are are
really close also. So, um, I think she's
just as happy and, um, I'm really
excited because we played each other in
the state champ state championship game
my senior year against each other. Um,
and then we came together at Texas to to
play together and uh, now I guess we're
going to be teammates again. And man,
it's so awesome. Who would have thought,
you know, when we went out there as
captains, state championship game that
it would turn into teammates in the NFL
in Miami. So, pretty awesome.
>> And what do you think it'll do for you
to have uh familiar faces in not only
him, but then also coming in uh in the
same draft class as a couple of your
Longhorn teammates? Yeah, I mean it's so
awesome to me to have that familiar
faces around me and knowing that you got
to learn a lot as a rookie and you got
to you know, you know, be humble and and
uh you know, not say a word and just
come in and earn your stripes first by
through work and um effort and and just
being a good teammate. And so, you know,
Quinn can teach me what it what it's
like to to do the good things of a
rookie and to do the bad things a
rookie. And he can tell me, you know,
all the little things that you need to
know. And so, I'm going to be leaning on
Quinn. Uh time.
>> Excellent. Appreciate it. Thank you.
>> Sure.
>> Chris.
>> Hey, Michael. Chris Perkins from the
South Florida Sunset. How you doing?
>> Good. How you doing, Chris?
>> I'm doing good. I'm doing good. I
remember talking to you at the Senior
Bowl when you were up on the podium. I
asked you about NIL and transfer portal.
You gave me a great answer, so I
appreciate that. Um, I want to ask you
whether you view yourself as an underdog
come going to Texas as a as a walk-on
and being a lower round draft pick. On
the other hand, you did go to the
University of Texas. You were an
all-American and you did get drafted.
You're not a UDFA. So, do you view
yourself as an underdog or how do you
view yourself coming into this?
>> Yeah, I mean, I'll always be an underdog
in my opinion. Um, you know, I think,
you know, rookies is essentially a
walk-on all over again because no matter
besides maybe the first round, no matter
what pick you got picked, um, UFA second
through seven, you got to go earn your
stripes and they're they're going to
look at you just as the same as they
look at somebody else. And, um, I mean,
you use that as my advantage because
there's no politics, you know, when it
when it comes to production and it comes
to the NFL, um, like some other places.
So, it's about it's about money. It's
about who can produce. It's about who's
the best fit and who can learn the
system the quickest and and stay there
and stick. And so, um, I'm definitely
looked as an underdog and I I want to
keep that underdog mentality, keep that
chip on my shoulder. Um, so I'm really
excited for it. But, you know, this is
the first time somebody's actually
picked me. I haven't, you know, you
know, I didn't get recruited in high
school, barely anything. And, um, you
know, high school, I was JB team my
sophomore year. So, this is my first
time somebody's really picked up the
phone and said, "Michael Zap, we want
you." And so, that means a lot. And, you
know, I owe a lot to these coaches that
they believe in me. I got to go make
them right.
>> And special teams, I mean, is that going
to be crucial to you making the 53, do
you think?
>> Of course. Yeah. Um, obviously my goal
is to play on defense and play on
special teams. So, um, you know, I'm
going to do everything I can to learn as
much special teams I am is going to
learn defense, too. I think everybody,
you know, goes in there as like, I just
got drafted as a safety. That's true.
Yes, I'm going to do everything to learn
everything about a safety and try to go
earn a starting job, but um you know,
special teams is just as important. And
so, um I'm going to be really excited to
to figure out what, you know, what spots
and play on special teams and uh grind
my butt off to to try to go earn a
starting job at special teams as well.
>> All right. Thanks, Michael. Nice to see
you,
>> Travis.
>> Hey, Michael. What's up, man? Congrats
and welcome to South Florida.
>> Thank you, Travis.
>> I wanted to ask you, man, cuz stories
like yours to me are the best part of
sports. You know, I don't know the odds
of going from walk-on to draft pick, but
I'm sure it's it's not very not very
large. I'm wondering if there was a
moment where it kind of clicked for you
at Texas where you thought maybe like,
shoot, I could play at the next level.
Did that occur to you at some point at
Texas? [snorts]
when I uh when I got some burn a little
bit uh my sophomore year, so red shirt
freshman year. Um I played a tight end
and he ended up getting drafted second
round and uh he didn't have a catch on
me the whole game and I was pretty much
manto man and I was like man I got to
get bigger and a little bit faster and I
got to keep earning my starting job
because I wasn't starting at the time at
Texas. I gota go earn a starting job but
you know what happens if the chips keep
aligning you keep working hard, keep
putting your head down. I think this can
become a reality. So, uh, I think this
is kind of a funny story. I, you know,
freshman year, I hadn't even got to
Texas yet. Um, you know, I was walking
on and I was at one of my sisters, she's
two grades above me at one of her
parties and, um, you know, one of our
closest family friends came up to me. He
was like, "So, what do you want to do
with this sport management major?" It's
like, "I don't really know, man. I mean,
like this and this." He was like, "I can
tell that's BS. Like, what do you really
want to do? Just say it. I don't care."
I was like, "I want to go to the NFL,
but I know I'm a walk-on and um you
know, I haven't even started at Texas
yet." And he goes, "Dude, it doesn't
matter, you know, where you're at right
now. If that's your dream, go chase it
and go say it confidently." So, ever
since then, when people asked, I said,
"I want to go to the NFL." And some
people probably laughed to me. Some
people probably talked behind my back
right after that. But that's what I
believe. And look at look at us now.
>> That's right. That's what I'm saying,
man. These stories are the best. You
talked about Quinn Yers a little bit
already, but I'd love to get a scouting
report from you on our other two new
teammates here that were past teammates.
What are we getting with DJ Campbell and
Trey Moore here in Miami?
>> Yeah, I mean, obviously coaches talked
about it all the time in these press
conferences about the versatility. I
think that that shines with Trey Moore.
Um, he came in from UTSA as an edge guy
and was I think had one of the most
sacks in the country. Uh, came in and we
had some really good edges at Texas,
too. So, they're rotating and he's
getting a bunch of sacks. And then
Anthony Hill, you know, breaks his
wrist. Last game of the season, he goes
starts at off the ball Mike backer
wearing the green dot. And so, you know,
he's so versatile. Um, I think for for
DJ, um, you know, his athletic ability,
I don't know if y'all ever watched him
as a high school recruit, but he was a
fivestar. He was one of the biggest, you
know, recruits we got in in the last
four years, five years that I was there.
And, um, it was because of his talent
um, and his athletic ability as an O
lineman. So, he's really physical. he'll
let you know, too. So, it was a lot of
fun going back and forth with him. Four
years at Texas.
>> Awesome. Hey, man. Thanks, and congrats
again.
>> Yes, sir. Thanks, Travis.
>> Joe.
>> Hey, Michael. It's Joe Shott at the Palm
Beach Post. Nice to meet you,
>> man. Nice to meet you, Joe.
>> When Ryan Tanahill was at Texas A&M, he
was going into his last season, and I
remember I asked him, "So, do you think
you want to be try quarterback or
receiver in the NFL?" I felt dumb later
because I had no idea that he was gonna
be a first round pick as a quarterback.
>> So, you kind That's pretty awesome.
[clears throat]
>> You kind of never know [laughter]
where guys what what what a guy can do.
You know what I mean? You left out the
best part of the Quinn Ears Texas 6A
state championship game. Uh can you
please tell us who won and if you made
any plays in that game?
I like to uh I like the film to speak
for itself, but uh Westlake Shafts, my
team won, and I uh picked off Quinn
twice. So, [laughter]
>> it says here, one of the picks, I have
to find the video, was a one-handed
grab. Is it Was that a pretty good OBJ
type grab or what?
>> At at the time, that was probably the
coolest moment of my life because it was
uh it was Sports Center top 10 in it.
Number two was Aaron Rogers. Number one
was little Michael Taft walk on at
University of Texas. So, uh, pretty cool
to know that, you know, you jumped over
A-Rod on Sports Center top 10.
>> That's awesome. Nice to meet you.
Welcome.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you, Joe.
>> Isaiah,
>> uh, just two quick uh, questions for me.
Just first one, who was the tight end
that you mentioned uh, that you lined up
again? You care to share that name or do
we need to duo? [laughter]
>> I'm gonna I'm gonna keep it to myself,
but uh, cool.
>> Yeah, he went second round, so
[laughter]
>> All right, that's all I needed. That's
all I needed. And then, oh, actually,
yeah, that that was it actually.
Appreciate you.
>> Yes, sir. Is there
>> Omar?
>> Michael, is your voice horse or is that
how you normally talk?
>> Totally horse. Y'all are going to get
used to it. So, after every game, the
media guy came up to me and gave me a
cough drop. So, uh, I lose it pretty
quick when I'm playing football. This
time, I wasn't playing football on
Saturday. I was just doing a lot of
screaming and celebrating. So, pretty
horse still.
>> What What was that like? I mean, did you
know or have the a level of absolute
confidence that you would be drafted?
>> I mean, obviously there's always doubt
that creeps in your mind, but um you
know, I was pretty confident that I was
going to get drafted just based off the
feedback and um you know, it's pretty
cool. That morning, my my agent was
going through all the teams and and I
vividly remember being like, "All right,
well, what about Miami? They had a
fourth round grade on me." He was like,
"Yeah, you know, we'll see what happens.
I don't know if they'll take a safety
here, but that could be a possibility."
He said some other teams before then. He
was like, you know, I bet there's other
teams that grab you in the fourth before
their pick. So, um I wouldn't expect
them, but it's pretty cool that that I
ended up mentioning Miami. That was the
only team that I asked my agent about at
8:30 a.m. in the morning. And um man,
the experience was so awesome. And I had
so many of my I just posted a picture of
all the all the you know, past teammates
that were there um you know, at the at
the house for the draft. And to to show
the love that they had for me is is so
awesome. Yeah, you seem like a pretty
popular guy. Is it just the story, the
charisma, your personality? I I I gotta
admit you you you have I I'm pretty good
at this. And you have that head coach GM
kind of feel to you.
>> Um what what do you want to do when you
finish playing?
>> I don't know. I I know for sure I want
to be a leader in life. Um you know,
I've always had a plan A type of a type
of mindset just cuz I had to. you know,
the story that I was living, the, you
know, the way that God was giving me,
you know, B team and then walk on and
and always the underdog story. I had to
just have a plan A because the second
that I told myself, you know, maybe
let's look into a plan B is the second
that, you know, I I wasn't going to make
it. And so, it's the mindset that I had
to have. And um, as far as the the
popular gene, I I don't know about all
that, but I think I just love a lot. I
have a lot of joy. And I feel like
that's that's all you can do in this
life is, you know, it goes by quick. And
um there's there's no point of of being
angry. Obviously, I'm not perfect. I I
fail a ton, but I love to have joy in my
life. And I love to, you know, just be
around people that that share the same,
you know, mindset as me.
>> And one final question, cuz they have
you listed as 190 pounds. Is is that
like the the I put on the most weight I
ever I I had to play I had to get to for
the combine, or are you naturally like
at 190?
>> I'm 194 right now. So, um, you know, I
think at [clears throat] the combine,
you know, you fly in there and it's a I
was in California, so I had to take two
connecting flights. You don't eat
anything cuz they're taking a picture of
you in your underwear, so you better eat
healthy. [laughter]
Um, and then that whole that whole week
it's 6:00 a.m. to 11:00 p.m. You're
going and going and going and um, you
know, you're getting medical exams and
this and that and the other. And so the
only time you were able to eat was your
your agent or your trainer would Door
Dash uh Uber Eatats and and would get
you Chipotle or something like that. And
um so you know, I wish I could show that
I was 1944 because that helped, but I I
left San Diego for the combine at 195
and uh I guess I didn't chug enough
water that morning to weigh in.
[laughter]